Krishna Teja Tangaturi

Lead Android Developer & Architect

Contact

Address

Miyapur Hyderabad, TG, 5<u>00034</u>

Phone

9676316323

E-mail

teja.tangaturi@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktthealmighty/

Skills

Android (SDK)

Excellent

Java

Excellent

Kotlin

Very Good

NodeJS

Very Good

SwiftUI

Good 2

Firebase

Very Good

Gifted Android Developer offering more than 10 years of experience in demanding environments and broad range of industries including e-commerce, wearables, education, digital-twins, remote inspections/audits. Skilled in directing development with creative and performance-oriented approach. Well-organized and customerfocused with proven skills in project management and team leadership.

Work History

2020-10 -Current

Lead Android Developer

PSC Biotech, Hyderabad, Telangana

- Developed apps for Remote Inspections and Audits on Google Glass EE2 and Realwear wearables
- Ported zoom meetings on to Google Glass EE2 and Realwear
- Helped to automate biotech plant operations with OCR and Image analytics
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Integrated Insta 360 video stream into zoom meetings for remote conferences

2018-01 -2020-09

Director of Platform

XYZ Innovations Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Managed 4 projects simultaneously and met deadlines on time.
- Contributed to vision and high-level technical concepts spanning technology and business.
- Executing product backlog, sprint backlog, roadmap and release plan.
- Supporting team by reducing churn and waste, removing blockers, escalating issues and helping to mentor and grow team members.
- Cultivating highly effective relationships with internal business partners like product management, technical leads, operations, service and support

2015-12 -2017-12

Lead Android Developer

MySmartPrice Web Technology Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

• Collaborated with internal and external teams -



Product Managers, Engineers, Designers, and Marketers to conceptualize, build, test and realize new features.

- Implementing complex User Interfaces for MySmartPrice Android application.
- Standardized and enforced coding best practices, including optimizing apps for performance.
- Mentored and guided team of 4 members ensuring all were trained in product knowledge and capable of performing assigned duties.

2014-10 -2015-11

Senior Android Developer

Hug Innovations Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Implemented Bluetooth communication between android mobile and wearable device.
- Implemented Google maps customizations and places/near-by locations services
- Developed Custom graphs/charts.
- Implemented push notification setup handling over 10k notifications/day.

2012-01 -2014-10

Android Developer

Edutor Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Mobile Device Management Controlling around 500 android devices over internet.
- Usage Tracking Tracking user actions and content usage statistics and updating them on to cloud.
- Over-The-Air upgrades.
- Developed and installed several security models and policies on android devices.

Languages

English	
	Very Good
Hindi	
	Very Good
Telugu	
	Excellent

Education

2010-04

2010-07 -	Master of Science: Information Technology
2012-04	International Institute Of Information Technology - Hyderabad
2006-08 -	Bachelor of Science: Information

Technology Dhirubhai Ambani Institute Of Information Techno. -Ahmedabad